Finding Aid for the National Gay and Lesbian Task Force records LSC.2205
UCLA Library Special Collections
National Gay and Lesbian Task Force records
1980-1989
UCLA Library Special Collections
National Gay and Lesbian Task Force (U.S.)
LSC.2205
0.4 linear feet (1 box)
The National Gay and Lesbian Task Force (currently the National LGBTQ Task Force) is an American non-profit organization focused on building, supporting and educating a grassroots community around LGBTQ rights and causes. This collection contains photocopies of administrative documents and research materials from the West Hollywood office of the National Gay and Lesbian Task Force during the 1980s.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Jean Conger, 2013.
This collection is part of an outreach and collection-building partnership between the June L. Mazer Lesbian Archives, the UCLA Center for the Study of Women (CSW), and the UCLA Library.
Sponsor
The June L. Mazer Lesbian Archive at UCLA is an outreach and collection-building partnership between the June L. Mazer Lesbian Archives, the UCLA Center for the Study of Women (CSW), and the UCLA Library. These collections expand the pool of primary source materials available to researchers and to the community at large. This partnership was initiated by CSW and is funded by the National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH) to inventory, organize, preserve, and digitize more than eighty Mazer collections pertaining to lesbian and feminist activism and writings.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9973847763606533
Biography
The National Gay Task Force was founded in 1973 by Dr. Howard Brown, Dr. Bruce Voeller, Reverend Robert Carter and Dr. Frank Kameny. It then transformed into the National Gay and Lesbian Task Force and currently operates as the National LGBTQ Task Force. Focused on creating and supporting grassroots power of the lesbian, gay, bisexual and transgender communities, the National Gay and Lesbian Task Force has offices in multiple cities and engages with a wide range of activities and opportunities for outreach. It runs Creating Change, the National Conference for LGBT Equality, and operates a Policy Institute, a think tank that conducts social science research, policy analysis, strategy development, public education and advocacy.
Scope and Content
This collection contains photocopies of administrative documents and research materials from the West Hollywood office of the National Gay and Lesbian Task Force during the 1980s. Included are correspondence, agendas, surveys, and data collection projects about vulnerable populations, homophobic violence, and HIV/AIDS public service availability documenting the work of various Task Force members such as Kim Kralj, and prepared by the Task Force and other non-profit organizations such as the Gay and Lesbian Community Services Center. The materials in this collection represent the extent to which the National Gay and Lesbian Task Force was involved in local Los Angeles activism, conducting community needs assessments, engaging with local businesses, and becoming involved in local politics.
Organization and Arrangement
Materials arranged by type.
Related Material
Kim Kralj papers (Collection 2157). Available at Library Special Collections, Charles E. Young Research Library, UCLA.
Gay and Lesbian Community Services Center records (Collection 2204). Available at Library Special Collections, Charles E. Young Research Library, UCLA.
Related Online Items Available
Portions of the June L. Mazer Lesbian Archives Subject Files have been digitized and are available online: June L. Mazer Lesbian Archives Subject Files (863 items)
Gay liberation movement -- United States.; Gay rights -- United States.; June L. Mazer Lesbian Archives; June L. Mazer Lesbian Archive at UCLA; National Gay and Lesbian Task Force (U.S.) -- Archives
- Research materials, 1980-1989 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Content
  Photocopies of reports, magazine articles, and clippings of stories from newspapers such as the Los Angeles Times and The Bay Area Reporter affecting gays and lesbians in Los Angeles during the 1980s.
- Anti-Violence Hotline Reports, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Reports prepared by the Gay and Lesbian Community Services Center on violence committed against gay and lesbian people in the city of Los Angeles.
- Monthly Project Services reports, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Reports of activities and plans proposed by different organizations to the City of West Hollywood on a monthly basis.
- Meeting agendas, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Agendas from meetings of the Los Angeles chapter of the National Gay and Lesbian Task Force.
- City of West Hollywood Council resolutions, 1986-1988 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Photocopies of select resolutions and ordinances passed during City of West Hollywood Council meetings between 1986 and 1988.
- Gay and Lesbian Task Force reports, circa 1987 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Includes the Gay and Lesbian Task Force's final report as well as the West Hollywood Women's Issues Task Force's final report to the City of West Hollywood.
- Memoranda and correspondence, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Photocopies of memos and correspondence regarding the activities and concerns of the Gay and Lesbian Task Force.
- Meeting minutes, correspondence, and memoranda, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Photocopies of minutes from weekly meetings of the Gay and Lesbian Task Force as well as related correspondence and memoranda.
- Community lists and data collection, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Addresses and contact information of businesses and members as well as collected data from surveys.
- LIFE (Lobby for Individual Freedom and Equality) legislative updates, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Reports and updates from LIFE (the Lobby for Individual Freedom and Equality) concerning legislative actions and movements concerning gays and lesbians, in particular those with HIV/AIDS.
- Survey for persons with AIDS/ARC, undated (Box 1, Folder 11-12)
  Photocopies of survey put together by the Gay and Lesbian Task Force attempting to collate information about the lifestyles, habits, histories and experiences with public services and medical treatment of those diagnosed with Human Immunodeficiency Virus (HIV) and/or AIDS-related complex (ACR).
- Survey for West Hollywood businesses, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Survey put together by the Gay and Lesbian Task Force to gather data on the businesses operating within West Hollywood.